nessy.com 2019-11-05

# Nessy - Privacy Policy

### Scope of this Privacy Policy

This Privacy Policy applies to all Nessy brands, products, and services. It describes what information we collect and how it is used and shared. Our online services (which we refer to as the “Nessy Platform”) are available through the nessy.com and learn.nessy.com websites. Our tablet and smartphone apps (which we refer to as the “Nessy Apps”) are available to purchase and download through the Apple App Store, Google Play Store and the Amazon App Store.

This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through the Nessy Platform and Nessy Apps and held in digital format. This Privacy Policy does not apply to information collected and stored offline.

### Online Safety

Nessy Learning is committed to maintaining a high level of online safety for children, parents and teachers. Nessy Learning does not allow third-party companies to advertise through the Nessy Platform or Nessy Apps, and we are fully committed to keeping the Nessy Platform and Nessy Apps free from advertising.

Nessy Learning provides, completely free of charge, a safe web browser (which we refer to as the “Nessy Browser”) that can be downloaded from the nessy.com website and used to access the Nessy Platform. The Nessy Browser allows children (which we refer to as “students”) to access the full Nessy Platform whilst preventing them from accessing any content or websites other than those that are provided through the Nessy Platform.

Please help ensure that students have a safe and rewarding online experience by encouraging responsible information practices. Several enhanced security features can be accessed and managed through the password protected Admin & Reports portal.

If you are under 13 years you will need your parent’s permission before you can create a nessy.com account.

### What information do we collect?

The security of your personal information is important to Nessy. Any information you provide will be held securely and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and the General Data Protection Regulation 2018. Nessy will never sell or rent any of your personal information.

The Nessy Platform collects personal information from you in the following ways:

  * When you register for a free trial
  * When you purchase a product or service
  * When you add a student
  * When you request support from Nessy’s customer support team
  * When you log in
  * When you enter a contest or respond to a survey
  * When you request any score or results to be emailed to you from a Nessy App

Information about a student’s progress through the Nessy Platform is collected whenever they interact with the program. This progress information includes information about reading, spelling, writing, numeracy and typing skills as well as how long they have spent using the platform.

When you use the nessy.com website, we gather anonymous usage statistics via various analytics platforms to enable us to improve our website and offering.

### How do we store your information?

We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information. We have put in place appropriate physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard your data and prevent unauthorised access or use of the information we collect online.

Your personal information is stored on secure databases that are behind secured networks. Direct access to these databases is very strictly limited and controlled. Only a limited number of Nessy employees have access to such systems. All Nessy employees are contractually obligated to respect your information and keep this information confidential and secure.

The Nessy Platform is only accessible via a secure (SSL) connection. Any sensitive information you supply (such as passwords) is stored via an SSL connection to our databases using one-way hashing (an extremely secure method of encryption), meaning nobody can view this sensitive information once it has been saved to the database.

### How do we use this information?

We may use the information we collect from you in the following ways:

  * To personalise your experience on the nessy.com website, allowing us to deliver the type of content and product offerings in which you are most interested
  * To allow us to better service you in responding to your customer service requests
  * To facilitate the purchase of Nessy products and services
  * To allow the renewal of any subscriptions purchased through the nessy.com website
  * To send you reports via email of student progress through the Nessy Platform
  * To inform you about updates and improvements to the Nessy Platform including information about new and upcoming applications
  * To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature
  * To benchmark the usage of Nessy Apps and improve the features available through them

### How is this information shared?

We work with third party companies to help provide and improve the Nessy service. Where necessary these companies have been checked to ensure they maintain the same levels of privacy and security that Nessy does.

As part of helping you get the most effective use of the Nessy platform we may produce a progress report for your account to share with you. One of our Nessy advisors will first read through and analyse this report so they can offer advice on how best to use Nessy to suit your needs.

We also work with the academic community to facilitate research into areas surrounding learning difficulties and how best to tackle them. From time to time we will provide totally anonymised user data to a small number of trusted academic researchers to enable this research.

### How can you manage or delete information about yourself?

To view or modify your account data including any active subscriptions you have for the Nessy Platform, you can log in via the nessy.com website. You can view or modify any student data through the Admin & Reporting portal.

If you wish to delete your online account and corresponding data from the Nessy Platform, please contact our customer support team via the nessy.com website. Deletion of your account information will prevent any future access to the Nessy Platform. Please note that we may keep some information about individual sales transactions for accounting purposes (this is a legal requirement).

### How to contact Nessy with questions

We welcome your questions, comments, and concerns about privacy. If you have any questions about this privacy policy or any questions in general about privacy of data on the Nessy platform, please contact our customer support team via the nessy.com website.

The data controller responsible for your information is Nessy Learning Ltd, which you can contact online or by post to:

Nessy Learning Ltd  
Royal London Buildings  
42-43 Baldwin Street  
Bristol  
BS1 1PN

### Cookie Policy

For information about what cookies we use and why we use them, please see our [cookie policy](https://www.nessy.com/us/cookie-policy).

### Terms and Conditions

Please visit our [Terms and Conditions](https://www.nessy.com/us/terms-and-conditions) section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of Nessy services and products.

### How will we notify you of changes to this policy?

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on our [privacy policy](https://www.nessy.com/us/privacy-policy) page and display them when you login to the Admin & Reporting portal. Policy changes will apply only to information collected after the date of the change. This policy was last modified on May 8th 2018.
